<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./Carovex.png" type="Manipulator"
    xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">

    <name>Players Selector</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Query basic player information from the Football API
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
            Lightweight node for querying basic player information from the Football API.
            This node returns essential player data only, making it ideal for browsing, filtering,
            and selecting players for further analysis.
            </p>
            <p>
            Unlike the full Players node, this selector does NOT retrieve detailed season statistics.
            This makes queries faster and more efficient for browsing large player rosters.
            </p>
            <p>
            The output can be filtered using KNIME's Row Filter or other filtering nodes, then fed into
            the Player Stats node to retrieve comprehensive match-by-match statistics for only the
            selected players.
            </p>
            <p>
            Supports querying players by team, searching by name, or looking up specific player IDs.
            </p>
        </intro>

        <option name="Query Type">
            Select how to query players:
            <ul>
                <li><b>Players by Team:</b> Get all players for a specific team in a season</li>
                <li><b>Search by Name:</b> Find players by name (supports optional team filter)</li>
                <li><b>By Player ID:</b> Get specific player by ID</li>
            </ul>
        </option>

        <option name="League">
            Select the league. Populated from reference data input.
            Used for filtering results when searching by name.
        </option>

        <option name="Season">
            Select the season year. Populated from reference data input.
            Required for all query types.
        </option>

        <option name="Team">
            Select team for "Players by Team" queries, or optional team filter for name searches.
        </option>

        <option name="Player Name">
            For name search queries, enter the player name or partial name to search.
        </option>

        <option name="Player ID">
            For player ID queries, specify the numeric player ID or comma-separated list of IDs.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="API Connection">
            API-Sports connection from the API-Connector node
        </inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Reference Data">
            Reference data (leagues, seasons, teams) from the Reference Data Loader node
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Basic Player Info">
            Table containing basic player data with 9 columns: Player_ID, Name, Firstname, Lastname,
            Nationality, Age, Team_ID, Team_Name, Position.

            This output can be filtered and fed into the Player Stats node to retrieve comprehensive
            match-by-match statistics for selected players only.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
